<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>code.steadman.io</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://code.steadman.io/feeds/all.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://code.steadman.io/</id><updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>A web framework for the creative mind</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/a-web-framework-for-the-creative-mind.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2015-05-31:a-web-framework-for-the-creative-mind.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/135740367" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>Telestrap</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/telestrap.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2015-04-09:telestrap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a Bootstrap theme with a &lt;a href="http://www.fonts2u.com/teletext-regular-regular.font"&gt;Teletext-style font&lt;/a&gt;,
inspired by the text services we used to get before the Web and digital TV
ruined everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's pretty much just a novely project, so don't expect much support :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://github.com/iamsteadman/telestrap"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-git-branch"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Fork it on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bootstrap"></category><category term="teletext"></category></entry><entry><title>ansible-ffmpeg</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/ansible-ffmpeg.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2015-01-30:ansible-ffmpeg.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/iamsteadman/1072bcd768e967cf66f3.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Trace</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/trace.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2014-09-02:trace.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Services for Education commissioned &lt;a href="http://substrakt.com/"&gt;Substrakt&lt;/a&gt;, my
employer to build a SaaS platform for the education sector, following changes in
legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum design, assessment and reporting tool allows teachers to create a
sequence of work for pupils and track their progress through the National
Curriculum. Headteachers and auditors can see reports of pupil, cohort and
whole-school progress in realtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site runs Django 1.6 on AWS, using Elastic Beanstalk to provision and deploy
servers in a scalable architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most complex projects I've worked on, and has tested my maths
skills to the limit. The reports require complex calculations which have to be
performed quickly. This means a lot of raw SQL as well as parsing data within
Python... and knowing when such jobs should be performed at the database or
business-logic level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python code is written entirely by me, with 99% of the interface built by me
using Twitter Bootstrap, with design and user-interface work provided almost
entirely by Substrakt's Creative Director, Jim Braithwaite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111732346" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how sequences of work are designed, by picking statements from
the National Curriculum, and grouping them together, ordering them and providing
notes as teaching aids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assessment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111762755" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video demonstrates the assessment area, where pupils' progress is marked.
Completed assessments can be audited by another person, internal or external to
the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111767419" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows the reports that can be generated via the system, which queries
data in realtime, via raw SQL queries that have been finely-tuned after months
of iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://s4etrace.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-eye"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Find out more about Trace
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>Django data provisioner</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/django-data-provisioner.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2014-07-14:django-data-provisioner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I need to do a bunch of frontend development for a site I'm working on, and I
needed a simple way to generate sample data that is sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, inspired by &lt;a href="http://ansible.com/"&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; I knocked up a data provisioning
system as a Django management command, that takes a YAML file defining the data
I want to generate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can take data from a JSON resource, likt the Random User API, and turn that
into User objects with Profile objects attached, to carry things like the
profile image, gender, date-of-birth and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It needn't be used to generate users; that's just the first thing I needed it to
do. It's intelligently nested, so if you need to create a foreign key
relationship, you just nest the two model statements and the management command
figures out the relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for linking models via many-to-many relationships, but in reverse.
Here you specify the fieldname you want, and tell the provisioner how many items
you want to use, and whether you want to pick the items starting at a row
number, or just choose them at random. You can also filter and exclude which
items are taken from the database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It automatically detects file fields and downloads remote images or picks files
from the filesystem. It does this intelligently, as it knows which model you're referencing, so looks in that app's directory to find the relevant file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://github.com/iamsteadman/bambu-gensite"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-git-branch"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Fork it on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="ansible"></category></entry><entry><title>Plunja.js</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/plunjajs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2014-07-01:plunjajs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Plunja is a simple JavaScript templating system that takes blocks of HTML stored
in &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags and renders them with context objects. It was inspired by
&lt;a href="http://jinja.pocoo.org/docs/"&gt;Jinja2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t need a JavaScript framework to use it, as you can define your own
custom locator (ie: a way of finding the template from the DOM). The built-in
locator uses jQuery, but it’s really simple to define your own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://github.com/iamsteadman/plunja"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-git-branch"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Fork it on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="javascript"></category></entry><entry><title>twopy</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/twopy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2014-03-04:twopy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/iamsteadman/9343536.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Primus</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/primus.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2013-09-30:primus.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customise the header image, background colours and navbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Converts WordPress menu classes into Bootstrap classes, rather than fiddle with Bootstrap's CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses &lt;a href="http://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/"&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/a&gt; icons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://github.com/iamsteadman/primus"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-git-branch"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Fork it on GitHub
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="bootstrap"></category></entry><entry><title>ReelLearning</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/reellearning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2013-09-15:reellearning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ReelLearning is a video training project for primary school teachers,
built by me at &lt;a href="http://substrakt.com/"&gt;Substrakt&lt;/a&gt; in Django, using Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally a Drupal website, I was asked to rebuild it, first running on a
Rackspace Red Hat server, then in 2014 we moved it to Amazon Web Services, using
Elastic Beanstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools sign up to ReelLearning to provide training for their teachers. While
the app doesn't handle the payment side, it does manage all of the account
creation, trial signups and user-created content. The catalogue is managed via
the Django admin, using the Grappelli skin. Videos uploaded via the site are
passed to Amazon S3 and served via CloudFront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Browse, search and view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114352311" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how users can browse the video catalogue and search it (via
the Haystack Django app).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Playlists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114352310" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video demonstrates how playlists are created and managed. They can be
shared with other members of a school, and also created by ReelLearning staff
and shared amongst all of the schools using the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Groups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114965612" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how users create and manage groups. These can be used to group
other users together, such as teachers in a specific year or subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="http://reellearning.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-eye"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Find out more about ReelLearning
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>MVC structures in WordPress plugins</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/mvc-structures-in-wordpress-plugins.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2013-06-14:mvc-structures-in-wordpress-plugins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/68363968" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="mvc"></category></entry><entry><title>A deer on ice</title><link href="http://code.steadman.io/a-deer-on-ice.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:code.steadman.io,2013-05-17:a-deer-on-ice.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/66555533" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Mark Steadman, and sometimes I feel - like certainly now - like a
deer on ice, just kind of panicking, scrabbling around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on my own here in Poland, I'm blind, so this is all quite a fun little
experience trying to get my head around the place, and I'm going to try and
battle through this really quickly as time is of the essence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the really nice things I've discovered about Poland is that I really like
pierogis. And this is a cat that looks like a pierogi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pierogi cat" src="http://www.highplainssigh.com/images/pierogi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So obviously that's got to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't clap, you're eating up my time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have a problem, obviously. I suck at people stuff. I'm really bad; I can
sort of manage like a group of 5, 10 people maybe, and after that I just start
to panic and everything just becomes "huh?" and I'm really frightened and geeky
and scared and shy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that also means that I kind of suck at communities. I've been doing a fair
bit on the web for ages and have never really been part of anything. So to give
you a little bit of background: I've been using Django since around 2009. In
2010 I was number 6 in Django Dash, and that was a project that I was basically
the sort of lead solo guy; all the other guys were teams. And also I built in
2008 and refactored something called TweetPaste which got used by the Guardian
in the UK and was recognised by Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I say this not as some kind of boasting thing. I'm merely trying to say that
I do stuff, but I'm sort of really crap at being... at joining in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I'm doing at the moment is something called Nymbol, and it's a mobile
CMS for physical objects. And I've got a toolset that I've built called Bambu
Tools, and it's basically just this gargantuan list of reusable apps that do
basically... I had a raft of ideas for ages, of stuff that I wanted to build and
I would have all these little ideas, and I started building up this massive
toolset that meant I could just go bang out an idea and all I had to build was
the idea itself. And if I wanted to productise that or commoditise it, I could
really easily, because I had everything, theoretically in place without much
configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the problem is, I'm kind of a nice guy, right? I try and do things the right
way. But we have some issues. So please don't attack me when I say that I've got
these things, there's no internationalisation which means there's no
localisation, there's no documentation, there aren't any tests; there's all
these things wrong with it, and that's simply because I haven't yet been at the
stage where I'm thinking I want to contribute to the community; this is just
stuff that's run for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I know that that's kind of unacceptable, but what I'm sort of trying to do
now is to stop doing it wrong and to start making a promise, and so I wanted to
make a little promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little video I made ages ago and it incapsulated this feeling of hope
and if you give hope a helping hand, then it can achieve some awesome things. So
there's been a lot of talk at this conference about how the Django community and
Python communities are fantastic and inclusive and there are great things we
can do and I want to really be a part of that, so obviously I've signed up for
the introduction to committing tomorrow, at the sprints, so I'm going to do my
utmost to be a real, functioning, valuable member of the community. So thank you
very much.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry></feed>