<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>code.steadman.io</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/portfolio.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Trace</title><link href="/portfolio/trace" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:,2014-09-02:portfolio/trace</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Services for Education commissioned &lt;a href="http://substrakt.com/"&gt;Substrakt&lt;/a&gt;, my
employer to build a SaaS platform for the education sector, following changes in
legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The curriculum design, assessment and reporting tool allows teachers to create a
sequence of work for pupils and track their progress through the National
Curriculum. Headteachers and auditors can see reports of pupil, cohort and
whole-school progress in realtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site runs Django 1.6 on AWS, using Elastic Beanstalk to provision and deploy
servers in a scalable architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most complex projects I've worked on, and has tested my maths
skills to the limit. The reports require complex calculations which have to be
performed quickly. This means a lot of raw SQL as well as parsing data within
Python... and knowing when such jobs should be performed at the database or
business-logic level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python code is written entirely by me, with 99% of the interface built by me
using Twitter Bootstrap, with design and user-interface work provided almost
entirely by Substrakt's Creative Director, Jim Braithwaite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111732346" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how sequences of work are designed, by picking statements from
the National Curriculum, and grouping them together, ordering them and providing
notes as teaching aids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Assessment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111762755" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video demonstrates the assessment area, where pupils' progress is marked.
Completed assessments can be audited by another person, internal or external to
the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reporting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/111767419" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows the reports that can be generated via the system, which queries
data in realtime, via raw SQL queries that have been finely-tuned after months
of iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="https://s4etrace.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-eye"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Find out more about Trace
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category></entry><entry><title>ReelLearning</title><link href="/portfolio/reellearning" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:,2013-09-15:portfolio/reellearning</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ReelLearning is a video training project for primary school teachers,
built by me at &lt;a href="http://substrakt.com/"&gt;Substrakt&lt;/a&gt; in Django, using Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally a Drupal website, I was asked to rebuild it, first running on a
Rackspace Red Hat server, then in 2014 we moved it to Amazon Web Services, using
Elastic Beanstalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools sign up to ReelLearning to provide training for their teachers. While
the app doesn't handle the payment side, it does manage all of the account
creation, trial signups and user-created content. The catalogue is managed via
the Django admin, using the Grappelli skin. Videos uploaded via the site are
passed to Amazon S3 and served via CloudFront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Browse, search and view&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114352311" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how users can browse the video catalogue and search it (via
the Haystack Django app).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Playlists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114352310" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video demonstrates how playlists are created and managed. They can be
shared with other members of a school, and also created by ReelLearning staff
and shared amongst all of the schools using the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Groups&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/114965612" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video shows how users create and manage groups. These can be used to group
other users together, such as teachers in a specific year or subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="btn" href="http://reellearning.co.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;span class="octicon octicon-eye"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    Find out more about ReelLearning
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category></entry></feed>