<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>code.steadman.io</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/talks.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>A web framework for the creative mind</title><link href="/talks/a-web-framework-for-the-creative-mind" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-31:talks/a-web-framework-for-the-creative-mind</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/135740367" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry><entry><title>MVC structures in WordPress plugins</title><link href="/talks/mvc-structures-in-wordpress-plugins" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:,2013-06-14:talks/mvc-structures-in-wordpress-plugins</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/68363968" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</summary><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="mvc"></category></entry><entry><title>A deer on ice</title><link href="/talks/a-deer-on-ice" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Steadman</name></author><id>tag:,2013-05-17:talks/a-deer-on-ice</id><summary type="html">&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/66555533" width="730" height="455" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Transcript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Mark Steadman, and sometimes I feel - like certainly now - like a
deer on ice, just kind of panicking, scrabbling around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm on my own here in Poland, I'm blind, so this is all quite a fun little
experience trying to get my head around the place, and I'm going to try and
battle through this really quickly as time is of the essence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the really nice things I've discovered about Poland is that I really like
pierogis. And this is a cat that looks like a pierogi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pierogi cat" src="http://www.highplainssigh.com/images/pierogi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So obviously that's got to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't clap, you're eating up my time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I have a problem, obviously. I suck at people stuff. I'm really bad; I can
sort of manage like a group of 5, 10 people maybe, and after that I just start
to panic and everything just becomes "huh?" and I'm really frightened and geeky
and scared and shy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that also means that I kind of suck at communities. I've been doing a fair
bit on the web for ages and have never really been part of anything. So to give
you a little bit of background: I've been using Django since around 2009. In
2010 I was number 6 in Django Dash, and that was a project that I was basically
the sort of lead solo guy; all the other guys were teams. And also I built in
2008 and refactored something called TweetPaste which got used by the Guardian
in the UK and was recognised by Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I say this not as some kind of boasting thing. I'm merely trying to say that
I do stuff, but I'm sort of really crap at being... at joining in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I'm doing at the moment is something called Nymbol, and it's a mobile
CMS for physical objects. And I've got a toolset that I've built called Bambu
Tools, and it's basically just this gargantuan list of reusable apps that do
basically... I had a raft of ideas for ages, of stuff that I wanted to build and
I would have all these little ideas, and I started building up this massive
toolset that meant I could just go bang out an idea and all I had to build was
the idea itself. And if I wanted to productise that or commoditise it, I could
really easily, because I had everything, theoretically in place without much
configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the problem is, I'm kind of a nice guy, right? I try and do things the right
way. But we have some issues. So please don't attack me when I say that I've got
these things, there's no internationalisation which means there's no
localisation, there's no documentation, there aren't any tests; there's all
these things wrong with it, and that's simply because I haven't yet been at the
stage where I'm thinking I want to contribute to the community; this is just
stuff that's run for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I know that that's kind of unacceptable, but what I'm sort of trying to do
now is to stop doing it wrong and to start making a promise, and so I wanted to
make a little promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little video I made ages ago and it incapsulated this feeling of hope
and if you give hope a helping hand, then it can achieve some awesome things. So
there's been a lot of talk at this conference about how the Django community and
Python communities are fantastic and inclusive and there are great things we
can do and I want to really be a part of that, so obviously I've signed up for
the introduction to committing tomorrow, at the sprints, so I'm going to do my
utmost to be a real, functioning, valuable member of the community. So thank you
very much.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="django"></category><category term="djangocon"></category></entry></feed>